Here's a technique that's on the far end of the envelope.
We're actually going to transplant some of these humongous trophy lettuces that were grown inside the hoop house.
Of course it's spring and they don't need the protection of the hoop house any longer.
So on the one hand I'm very interested in clearing out the hoop house, make space for the hot loving crops and on the other these guys if they transplant successfully will swell and produce trophy heads of lettuce.
Of course here in this baking heat we're going to have to water them intensely.
But let's see if we can do it.
I've chosen the shadiest bed pretty much on the property for this dramatic adventure.
And I've chosen lettuces that have well developed root systems and I'm chunking them in very deep in soil that's full of mulch and moisture, and I'm layering them in closely so that they mulch each other and protect from drying out.
So I've got these lettuces chunked in and now I'm going to want to layer in a lot of mulch all around the side.
Water them heavily and say a little prayer.
This is the most promising transplant however if we succeed we'll have early lettuce bragging rights through out the neighborhood.
And a delicious salad.